Henry and Elizabeth Eugle Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Henry And Elizabeth Eugle Collection
1930 - 1984
NPkMC-222-113
1.5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Henry Eugle; Elizabeth Eugle
The collection consists of programs and promotional material for concerts and other music-related events which took place in the Hudson Valley between 1930 and 1984. Many of the programs come from performances by college bands and choirs in the area including Vassar College and Middlebury College as well as from performances by the Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra.
Collection Overview
Music of the Hudson Valley Collection contains concert programs, promotional leaflets, photographs, advertisements and newspaper articles covering vocal and orchestral performances in the Hudson Valley between 1930 and 1984.
Acquisitions Information
This collection was donated to Marist College by Henry and Elizabeth Eugle.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Collection is arranged into eight series: 1) The Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra, 2) Vassar College Department of Music, 3) Vassar Brothers Insititute, 4) Middlebury College, 5) The Bardavon Opera House, 6) Nadia Koutzen, 7) Miscellaneous Concert Porgrams, 8) Miscellany.
Materials are arranged chronologically or alphabetically
- 1. The Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra, 1960 - 1982; 1; 0.75 linear feet Box: 1 Folders: 1 - 27
  Series contains: Concert programs, photographs and newspaper articles about the Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra.
  Chronological
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert program 1960 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert program 1961-62 (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1968-69 (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1969-70 (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1970-71 (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1971-72 (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1972-73 (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1973-74 (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1974-75 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1975-76 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1976-77 (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1977-78 (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1978-79 (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1980-81 (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra concert programs 1981-82 (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Youth Orchestra concert program (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Virtuosi-In-Progress concert (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Youth Orchestra concert program January 13, 1981 (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Junior String Ensemble concert program January 18, 1981 (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Junior String Ensemble concert program (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra memorial concert concert -program November 8, 1981 (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - 1981-82 season promotional poster (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - “Open-Air Symphony Music at Rose Hill” program, postcards and (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Grant newspaper article (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra early photographs (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Philharmonic Orchestra donation card (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Itzhak Perlman performance advertisement (Folder 27, Box 1)
- 2.Vassar College Department of Music, 1966 - 1984; 2; 0.38 Linear Feet Box: 1 Folders: 26 - 88
  Series contains concert programs from performances by organizations within the Vassar College Department of Music.
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program May 4, 1966 (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program December 13, 1967 (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program March 5, 1968 (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Choir concert program April 21, 1968 (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 28, -1968 (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program May 5, 1968 (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 15, 1968 (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music presents The Hungarian String Quartet concert program November 18, 1968 (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program February 13, 1969 (2 copies) (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 3, 1969 (Folder 37, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 30, 1969 (Folder 38, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program September 24, 1969 (2 copies) (Folder 39, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 22, 1969 (Folder 40, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 22, 1970 (6 copies) (Folder 41, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program November 18, 1970 (Folder 42, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program December 8, 1971 (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program May 10, 1972 (Folder 44, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 16, 1973 (Folder 45, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program May 2, 1973 (Folder 46, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 3, 1973 (Folder 47, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 3, 1974 (Folder 48, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program May 1, 1974 (Folder 49, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 25, 1974 (Folder 50, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Choir concert program April 20, 1975 (Folder 51, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program November -24, 1975 (Folder 52, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program February 5, 1978 (Folder 53, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program September 15, 1978 (Folder 54, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program February 23, 1979 (Folder 55, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program March 4, 1979 (Folder 56, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program September 19, 1979 (Folder 57, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 17, 1979 (Folder 58, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program March 28, 1980 (Folder 59, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 11, 1980 (Folder 60, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program May 2, 1980 (Folder 61, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program January 25, 1981 (Folder 62, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program February 15, 1981 (Folder 63, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music presents the First Annual Festival of Third World Arts and Culture concert program -February 21, 1981 (Folder 64, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music Band and Choir concert program March 1, 1981 (Folder 65, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program March 25, -1981 (Folder 66, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program March 28, 1981 (Folder 67, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Choir presents Mozart’s Requiem April 5, 1981 (Folder 68, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 26, 1981 (Folder 69, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 9, 1981 (Folder 70, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music Music Major Alumni concert program October 10, 1981 (2 copies) (Folder 71, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 14, 1982 (Folder 72, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 21, 1982 (Folder 73, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 28, 1982 (Folder 74, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program August 29, 1982 (Folder 75, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program September 29, 1982 (2 copies) (Folder 76, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 21, 1982 (Folder 77, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program November 21, 1982 (2 copies) (Folder 78, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program November 23, 1982 (Folder 79, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Choir and Madrigal Singers present Lessons and Carols December 4, 1982 (Folder 80, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 6, 1983 (Folder 81, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 17, 1983 (Folder 82, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program April 27, 1983 (Folder 83, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program August 28, 1983 (Folder 84, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program September 14, 1983 (2 copies) (Folder 85, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program October 26, 1983 (Folder 86, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program November 2, 1983 (Folder 87, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Music concert program February -10, 1984 (Folder 88, Box 1)
- 3. Vassar Brothers Institute, 1974 - 1984; 3; 0.75 Linear Feet Box: 1 Folders: 89 - 99
  Series contains concert programs from performances bsy the members of the Vassar Brothers Institute.
  - concert program: Ninety-second Year 1974-1975 (Folder 89, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-third Year 1975-1976 (Folder 90, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-fourth Year 1976-1977 (Folder 91, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-fifth Year 1977-1978 (Folder 92, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-sixth Year 1978-1979 (Folder 93, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-seventh Year 1979-1980 (Folder 94, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-eighth Year 1980-1981 (Folder 95, Box 1)
  - concert program: Ninety-ninth Year 1981-1982 (Folder 96, Box 1)
  - concert program: One Hundredth Year 1982-1983 (Folder 97, Box 1)
  - concert program: One Hundred first Year 1983-1984 (Folder 98, Box 1)
  - “Music from the Pen of Charles Gilbert Spross” concert programs (Folder 99, Box 1)
- 4. Middlebury College, 1930 - 1931; 4; 0.25 Linear Feet Box: 1 Folders: 100 - 103
  Series contains concert programs from performances by organizations within Middlebury College.
  - Middlebury College Orchestra concert program May 2, 1930 (Folder 100, Box 1)
  - Middlebury College Women’s Glee Club concert program May 1, 1931 (Folder 101, Box 1)
  - Middlebury College Orchestra concert program May 15, 1931 (Folder 102, Box 1)
  - Twilight Musicale concert program June 14, 1931 (Folder 103, Box 1)
- 5. The Bardavon Opera House, 1930 - 1983; 5; 0.75 Linear Feet Box: 1 Folders: 104 - 110
  Series contains concert programs and promotional leaflets for performances taking place at the Bardavon Opera House.
  - Benefit Recital concert program December 9, 1979 (Folder 104, Box 1)
  - Benefit Recital concert program May 4, 1980 (Folder 105, Box 1)
  - Program for the 1980-81 Season (Folder 106, Box 1)
  - Concert Artists Guild One Plus One concert program (Folder 107, Box 1)
  - P-rogram for the 1982-83 Season (Folder 108, Box 1)
  - Concert Artists Guild the Arden Trio concert program and (Folder 109, Box 1)
  - Concert Artists Guild Alexander String Quartet concert program and promotional leaflet November 28, 1983 (Folder 110, Box 1)
- 6. Nadia Koutzen, 1930 - 1984; 6; 0.75 linear feet Box: 1 Folders: 111 - 116
  Series contains concert programs, newspaper articles and press releases featuring violinist Nadia Koutzen.
  - Town Hall Concert October 5, 1969 (Folder 111, Box 1)
  - Alice Tully Hall at Lincoln Center Concert October 20, 1970 (Folder 112, Box 1)
  - Alice Tully Hall at Lincoln Center Concert November 10, 1971 (Folder 113, Box 1)
  - Trio Concert: Inez, Nadia and George Koutzen March 23, 1975 (Folder 114, Box 1)
  - Nadia Koutzen Press Release (Folder 115, Box 1)
  - Newspaper Article: Violinist: Nadia Koutzen (Folder 116, Box 1)
- 7. Miscellaneous Concert Programs, 1930 - 1984; 7; Box: 1 Folders: 117 - 141
  Series contains unrelated concert programs from various concerts in the Hudson Valley.
  Alphabetical
  - Bucknell University Chorale 1980/81 concert tour (Folder 117, Box 1)
  - Cadets Fine Arts Forum presents Jean-Pierre Rampal (2 copies) (Folder 118, Box 1)
  - “Camelot” (Folder 119, Box 1)
  - Caramoor Center for Music and Arts (Folder 120, Box 1)
  - Cecilwood Summer Theatre (Folder 121, Box 1)
  - Chamber Music at First Presbyterian Church (Folder 122, Box 1)
  - Community United Methodist Church (Folder 123, Box 1)
  - Dartmouth Festival Orchestra (Folder 124, Box 1)
  - First Evangelical Lutheran Church Noontime Music Concert (Folder 125, Box 1)
  - “For Unto Us A Child Is Born” (Folder 126, Box 1)
  - Furman University Department of Music presents Keith Alan -Lockhart (Folder 127, Box 1)
  - Haverford College Orchestra (Folder 128, Box 1)
  - Hudson Valley Chamber Players (Folder 129, Box 1)
  - Jacob’s Pillow Dance Festival (Folder 130, Box 1)
  - Maverick Sunday Concerts (Folder 131, Box 1)
  - Old Southeast Church (Folder 132, Box 1)
  - State University of New Paltz (Folder 133, Box 1)
  - The Concord String Quartet (Folder 134, Box 1)
  - The Dutchess Community College presents The Guarneri String -Quartet (Folder 135, Box 1)
  - The Dutchess Hall Board of Managers presents Young Uck Kim (Folder 136, Box 1)
  - The East Fishkill Historical Society presents “Christmas Through the Centuries” (Folder 137, Box 1)
  - The fifth annual American Statistical Association Variety Show (Folder 138, Box 1)
  - The Hudson Valley Chamber Music Circle presents Laura George and Robert Pace (Folder 139, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Department of Drama and Africana Studies Program present “To Be Young, Gifted and Black” (Folder 140, Box 1)
  - Violin Recital (Folder 141, Box 1)
- 8. Miscellany, 1930 - 1984; 8; Box: 1 Folders: 142 - 148
  Series contains unrelated leaflets, flyers and pamphlets about various music-related events and items in the Hudson Valley.
  - “100% Chance of Rain” (Folder 142, Box 1)
  - Brewster Flute Festival flyer (Folder 143, Box 1)
  - Guarneri String Quartet (Folder 144, Box 1)
  - Michael Rabin (Folder 145, Box 1)
  - “Notebooks of Designs” and “Approximations” (Folder 146, Box 1)
  - The Sergio Peresson Violin and Viola (Folder 147, Box 1)
  - Vassar College Conferring of Degrees June 2, 1968 (Folder 148, Box 1)